SAMANTHA PONCE

CONTACT

Address: Brentwood NY 11717

Phone: 631-740-5034

Email: Samanthap once 5@gmail.com

https://samanthaponce.herokuapp.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samantha-

ponce-0bb6ba1a9/

https://github.com/Samanthaponce5

SKILLS

- Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, ReactJS, Redux, CSS, HTML, Restful API, PostgresSQL, GitHub
- Web-Based Software Engineering, Full-Stack, Frontend Web Development

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineering Intern, 11/2020 to Current MREN - San Diego, CA

 Collaborate with software engineers to develop/ test application procedures for system efficiency/ perform testing to uncover bugs and troubleshoot issues

Dental Assistant, 08/2020 to Current

American Dental - Hicksville, NY

 Educate patients on oral hygiene.
Prepared X-rays and general chair-side assisting procedures, including general, endo, and oral surgery.

Dental Assistant, 10/2019 to 03/2020 **Dental365** - Bellmore, NY

Dental Assistant, 01/2018 to 09/2019 **HRHCare** - Amityville, NY

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript-based programming with a background in Patient care which has provided me with strong skills in problem-solving, decision-making, organization, listening, and working under pressure. Can quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both teams and self-directed settings. Skilled at contributing to design, development and implementation as conscientious, upbeat and knowledgeable team member.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Certification: Web Development, 06/2020 Flatiron School - Manhattan, NY

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Jack's Journey -

<u>Frontend</u> - https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/thePlasticJourney-frontend <u>Backend</u>-https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/plasticTalesBackend <u>Site-https://jacksjourney.netlify.app/</u>

- An interactive educational site where users learn more about plastic pollution and the effects it has on the ocean.
- Built by using a ReactJS library, and a Rails-API backend using Postgres database.
- Implemented vanilla CSS for design

<u>ShopMart</u> - <u>Frontend</u>-https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/shopMart-front <u>Backend</u>-https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/shopMart-back <u>Site</u>-https://shop-mart-us.netlify.app/

- ShopMart is an e-commerce site where users can navigate through the store ranging from women, men, and kids clothing.
- Developed using a ReactJS library and a Rails-API backend using Postgres database and Redux.
- Applied vanilla CSS for design

<u>Omega Sound</u> - <u>Frontend</u>-https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/music-app <u>Backend</u> - https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/music-app-mod3 <u>Demo</u> - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wdjvTJGPTFE&feature=youtu.be

- Omega Sound is designed to let users search and listen to any songs they would like.
- Created by using Vanilla Javascript and Rails-API backend
- Employed the Spotify API for music
- Design created with vanilla CSS